Guide to the Peter Patrick Mendelsohn Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Peter Patrick Mendelsohn papers
1937-1959
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
1285
1285-001
Mendelsohn, Peter Patrick
1.36 Cubic Feet (4 boxes)
Papers of member of the Marine Cooks and Stewards Union regarding labor movement
Mr. Mendelsohn was a member of the Marine Cooks and Stewards Union.
Arranged in 5 series.
SERIES I, INCOMING LETTERS, 1957
SERIES II, LEGAL DOCUMENTS, 1952-1960
SERIES III, PAMPHLETS, 1950s
SERIES IV, NEWS CLIPPINGS, 1950s
SERIES V, MISCELLANEOUS, 1950s
Correspondence, clippings, legal documents, pamphlets, miscellany.
In 1957, the Coast Guard prohibited Mendelsohn from obtaining a Merchant Mariners Document. Case went to 9th Circuit Court. A transcript (2 vols.) is included. Also transcript of hearings before Seafarers' International Union. Included are about 150 ephemeral items regarding labor movement.
Access restricted: For terms of access, contact Special Collections for details.
Donated by Peter P. Mendelsohn, 11/12/1963.
Mendelsohn, Peter Patrick$vArchives; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Marine Cooks and Stewards Union; Seafarers' International Union of North America; International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union; Communist Party of the United States of America
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Labor History; Ships and Shipping
- INCOMING LETTERS, 1957; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Incoming Letters, 1957 (Box-folder 1/1)
    Letters from lawyer Lloyd E. McMurray to Commandant U.S. Coast Guard re denial by Coast Guard of a Merchant Mariner's document for Mendelsohn.
- LEGAL DOCUMENTS, 1952-1960; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/2-1/5)
  - Appeals, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Transcript of Lester et al vs. Parker, Mendelsohn, et al, U.S. Appeals Court 9th District (1 of 2), 1952 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Transcript of Lester et al vs. Parker, Mendelsohn, et al, U.S. Appeals Court 9th District (2 of 2), 1952 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Open Hearings Record RE: Complaints about Marine Cooks and Stewards Union, 1960 (Box-folder 1/5)
- PAMPHLETS, 1950s; SERIES III (Box-folder 2/1, Box 3-4)
  - Various Pamphlets (Fragile), c. 1950s (Box-folder 2/1)
  - (Unfoldered) Various Pamphlets (Fragile), c. 1940s-c. 1950s (Box 3)
  - (Unfoldered) Various Pamphlets (Fragile), c. 1940s-c. 1950s (Box 4)
- NEWS CLIPPINGS, 1950s; SERIES IV (Box-folder 2/2-2/3)
  - News Clippings, c. 1950s (Box-folder 2/2)
  - News Clippings, c. 1950s (Box-folder 2/3)
- MISCELLANEOUS, 1950s; SERIES V (Box 2)
  - (Unfoldered) Resolutions, Reports, Newsletters, c. 1950s (Box 2)